<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ddesotto\raw</title><link>https://ddesotto.com/</link><description>Recent content on ddesotto\raw</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Â© ddesotto</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 13:21:14 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ddesotto.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>diegodesotto\raw - the Why</title><link>https://ddesotto.com/posts/diegodesottoraw-thewhy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 13:21:14 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ddesotto.com/posts/diegodesottoraw-thewhy/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="why-ddesottoraw">Why ddesotto\raw&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I tried &lt;strong>WordPress&lt;/strong>. Now I&amp;rsquo;m here, which should be enough of a summary on how my &lt;strong>WordPress&lt;/strong> experience went (spoiler alert, do not recommend).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My blog, &lt;strong>bigdtalks.com&lt;/strong>, lasted one eternal year. While live, it hosted 15 posts with an average of 100 views/post, which is not bad, considering I had no prior experience. I built the site on Elementor (who calls that customizable?) and used BlueHost for buying the domain and hosting. Overall, the site came to a cost of around &lt;strong>$160&lt;/strong>. You might be wondering how much the ROI was. Well, the answer is not that good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At first I set up the site with the vision of having a possible source for passive income at the same time I shared my passion for acquiring knowledge. My idea was to use my already regular research sprees to then write articles on those topics. The perfect synergy. The problem is I became to focused on the former while forgetting the latter. A sidenote on building side-projects: &lt;strong>focus on quality, and money will follow&lt;/strong>. Lesson learned ðŸ‘.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Having said that, those &lt;strong>$160&lt;/strong> were probably the best investment I made in 2021 (and yes, I also bought &lt;strong>ETH&lt;/strong> ðŸ˜ƒ). I have learned a lot from &lt;strong>bigdtalks.com&lt;/strong>. I tried to reach perfection when, first, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really know what perfection was, and second, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t even tested if my idea was good enough. So for this blog, first publish, then ask. Good thing I can extrapolate it to practically any aspect of life. Thanks to my &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;failed&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> blog, I have now become more confident on making mistakes. I hope I learned the right lesson.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="why-github-pages--hugo">Why Github Pages + Hugo&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I have never been a Github groupie. Most of my projects went unnoticed to the general public, small scripts to automate basic tasks or to make use of a fancy algorithm I had learned about not so long ago. However, after I replaced &lt;strong>IG&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>TikTok&lt;/strong> with &lt;strong>Twitter&lt;/strong>, and having a small affection for HackerNews, where Github-related postings are a regular, hosting this website with GithubPages looked like an excellent way to make it both customizable &lt;em>and&lt;/em> simple. Oh yes, and also very cheap ðŸ’¸.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I decided on Hugo over Jekyll inspired by a fellow blogger (if I can call myself that) I found on HackerNews, &lt;strong>Kris Machowski&lt;/strong>. I really liked the simplicity and layout of his site and decided to use it as &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;inspiration&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>. By the way, his content is incredible, so please check it out &lt;a href="https://machow.ski">here&lt;/a>. You won&amp;rsquo;t regret it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I have decided to set a list of objectives before a start as a way of setting waypoints to measure the success of this blog. Nothing complicated, but more of a test.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>For 2022&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>20 blog posts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>100 newsletter subscribers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>100 visitors&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Building a useful relationship through the blog&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Overall&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Featured on HackerNews Top5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Having revenue&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Keep it running at least 5 years&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>