<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ddesotto\raw</title>
    <link>https://ddesotto.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ddesotto\raw</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© ddesotto</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 13:32:34 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ddesotto.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>But actually, what is dust?</title>
      <link>https://ddesotto.com/posts/what-is-dust/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 13:32:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ddesotto.com/posts/what-is-dust/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A table is table, a chair is a chair, and a lamp is, indeed, a lamp. At least from a broad perspective. You are also describing a lamp when saying &amp;ldquo;an illuminating device, generally composed of a stand and a bulb&amp;rdquo; The stand and the bulb are as much lamp as the object itself, but at the same time, completely different entities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole world is built by these types of constructions. If stubborn to break an object down into its building blocks infinetly, you will eventually reach atoms, protons and even quarks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usually enjoy breaking things down. Its usually an easy and entertaining task that helps me understand things better. Really recommend it to achieve comprehension. Its fun, as long as you don&amp;rsquo;t get stuck 😃.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence, dust is not fun. We all know what dust is. At least broadly. Now try to describe it. Break it down to its building blocks. Not so easy, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can probably reason dust is composed of suspended particles. Very small particles of no specific material. Yet we both know, this is not good enough. If we really want to understand dust, we need to understand &lt;strong&gt;what makes up dust&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;dust-the-basics&#34;&gt;Dust, the basics&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;callout&#34;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&#34;callout-inner&#34;&gt;
    ⚠️ DISCLAIMER. I will focus on airborne dust. Static dust is a bit boring 😏
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dust&lt;/strong&gt; is described by the National Geographic Society as &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;a collection of microscopic particles of material&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nationalgeographic.org/encyclopedia/dust/&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The World Health Organization describes such particles to be between 1 and 1000 μm (that&amp;rsquo;s 0.001mm or 10&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;-6&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; for the smallest, 1mm or 10&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;-3&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; for the biggest) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.who.int/occupational_health/publications/en/oehairbornedust3.pdf&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;. In other words, very small, only the biggest visible easily percieved by the human eye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not easy to classify particles this size. A block of wood is clearly wood, but what about a 0.01mm piece of wood? Would you be so sure about its composition after examining it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s more, &lt;em&gt;dust&lt;/em&gt; is not homogoneus through space. Dust inside you house is different to dust in a construction site and unrelated to dust in space. I&amp;rsquo;ve found house dust and space dust are the most interesting, so I will focus on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;home-dust&#34;&gt;Home dust&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A study conducted by Paloma Beamer found that house dust composition depends considerably on the ocuppants&amp;rsquo; habits. Around 60% is brought from the outside, stuck to clothes, hair and the soles of your shoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a consequence, home dust is mainly composed of &amp;ldquo;foreign&amp;rdquo; materials: pollen, dirt and, yes, dust mites (tiny pests that feed on dander and dead skin).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence why dust can be so annoying to people with allergies. Fun fact, dust mites where not a problem until the popularisation of textiles and cloths in homes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, dust is not only external: it can also be sourced inside the house. Small paint particles, bits of fiber and, drumroll please, dead skin! However, for those who claim dust is composed mostly of dead skin celss, I&amp;rsquo;m sorry to break down to you that it&amp;rsquo;s not. Most of these particles end up washed away when you shower or are left outised your home door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;space-dust&#34;&gt;Space dust&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space dust is probably the &lt;em&gt;entity&lt;/em&gt; that has most triggered my curiosity recently. When reading Isaac Asomov&amp;rsquo;s the Universe, I came to notice &amp;ldquo;space dust&amp;rdquo; is a recurring character that apparently plays a leading role in the story of our universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to your home, it is relatively easy to wrap your head around the fact that small particles of various materials may break off. The origin is easy to explain. But when it comes to the emptiness of space, where did this dust come from?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space, or cosmic dust, has a more defined classification than home dust. Astronomers usually classify it according to its location. Hence, intergalactic dust is found between galaxies, interstellar dust is suspended in galaxies and within stars, and circumplanetary dust lays between planets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When talking of space, size metrics become different to the ones used on Earth. What on our Earth may be considered massive may be a ridicule particle on space-scale. This explains why bigger particles in space can be considered dust. Even a one meter wide meteoroid could be considered space dust!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dust was at first anoying for researchers, as it screened observers from their objects of interest. However, as time passed by, dust proved to be an excellent source of information on the formation of the universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Particles that make up space dust usually are made of rock, ice, minerals or small organic compounds (sometimes a combination of the above). Of these, rock and carbon rich grains make up most of it inside the Solar System, but when leaving the Sun&amp;rsquo;s warmth behind, ice becomes the main character. That answers the &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;, but what about the &lt;em&gt;where&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cosmic Dust Analyzer project (CDA), which focused on dust surrounding Saturn, concluded, that, although an explanation for origin could be found in our system, some particles where concluded to be &lt;strong&gt;interstellar&lt;/strong&gt;. Some dust particles travelled millions of kilometers! To get to Saturn! (boring trip, I guess)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this doesn&amp;rsquo;t blow your mind, well, I don&amp;rsquo;t know what will. Well, maybe the fact that &lt;strong&gt;more than 100 tons of dust rain on the Earth every day&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carl Sagan correctly said &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are made of star-stuff&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;, and that star-stuff is space dust that evolved into more complex organisms. In other words, we &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; dust. So are stars, planets, meteors&amp;hellip; or at least they were millions, if not billions of years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;more-than-just-dust&#34;&gt;More than just &amp;lsquo;dust&amp;rsquo;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I find dust to be beautiful. Matter lives in a constant cycle breaking down to then come back together. In the center of it all: dust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is dust can be used as an opener to many essential questions about the universe. Whether you are trying to find answer about its origin, its composition or its structure, these small particles are bound to appear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is intriguing how something so small can cover something so big (the &amp;ldquo;emptiness&amp;rdquo; of space, which is, indeed, not empty). Yet it exists hidden to most minds which simply don&amp;rsquo;t want to make the effort of questioning their surroundings. It is sad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that you, dear reader, have opened a door in your brain that lets your curiosity out. Dust is just one example of the millions of unanswered questions we incomprehensibly take for granted. Don&amp;rsquo;t be like the crowd. Start making questions, even if it&amp;rsquo;s on stupid things like dust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;strong&gt;Dust&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;National Geographic Encyclopedia&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nationalgeographic.org/encyclopedia/dust/&#34;&gt;&amp;#x1f517;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;strong&gt;Hazard Prevention and Control in the Work Environment: Airborne Dust&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;World Health Organization&lt;/em&gt; pp 1-3 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.who.int/occupational_health/publications/en/oehairbornedust3.pdf&#34;&gt;&amp;#x1f517;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] &lt;strong&gt;Is Dust Mostly Dead Skin?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Veritasium&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jn5M48MVWyg&amp;amp;ab_channel=Veritasium&#34;&gt;&amp;#x1f517;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[5] &lt;strong&gt;Dust, Unsettled&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Janet Pelley&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubs.acs.org/doi/pdf/10.1021/acscentsci.7b00006&#34;&gt;&amp;#x1f517;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[6] &lt;strong&gt;Be Glad You Don&amp;rsquo;t Have to Dust in Space&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;NASA tumblr&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://nasa.tumblr.com/post/183772411259/be-glad-you-dont-have-to-dust-in-space&#34;&gt;&amp;#x1f517;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[7] &lt;strong&gt;Getting a Handle on How Much Cosmic Dust Hits Earth&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Nancy Atkins&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.universetoday.com/94392/getting-a-handle-on-how-much-cosmic-dust-hits-earth/#ixzz2j9WbyxMT&#34;&gt;&amp;#x1f517;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[8] &lt;strong&gt;Seven grains of interstellar dust reveal their secrets&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Andrew J Westphal&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.science.org/content/article/seven-grains-interstellar-dust-reveal-their-secrets&#34;&gt;&amp;#x1f517;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On things #2 - On Greeks and Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://ddesotto.com/posts/on-greeks-and-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 12:09:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ddesotto.com/posts/on-greeks-and-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I finished reading &lt;strong&gt;Plato&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Republic&lt;/em&gt;. The week before, &lt;em&gt;Rhetorics&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;Aristotle&lt;/strong&gt;. Not so long ago, &lt;em&gt;Meditations&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;Marcus Aurelius&lt;/strong&gt;. A complete ancient greek reading spree, which I most certainly most regret (they have me backordered on &lt;strong&gt;Seneca&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Letters from a Stoic&lt;/em&gt; 😢).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, what were these guys on when they wrote all this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I had to choose a phrase to represent my average impression, without doubt I would choose &amp;ldquo;wow&amp;hellip; what? wow&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every single one of those books blasted me with as much knowledge as it did with reflection. I don&amp;rsquo;t discard I was weirdly smiling throughout most of the chapters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s see if I can make you share, even if it&amp;rsquo;s only a little bit, of the my suprise. A group of men (women as well, don&amp;rsquo;t cancel me) decided &lt;em&gt;more than 2000 years ago&lt;/em&gt; something had to be done about knowledge. There simpl was not enough in accepting, they started &lt;em&gt;questioning&lt;/em&gt;. Why this? Why that? Next thing we know, they have built the base for humanities current understanding of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concepts developed in their essays make up for many disciplines of study nowadays. It is indeed impossible to think of Law &amp;amp; Poltics without considering the works of Plato and Aristotle, Pythagoras and Aristotle are staple in elementary math and even democracy, the keystone to the organization of most civilized societies, had its origins in ancient Greece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s go over a few of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;on-politics-and-thought&#34;&gt;On politics and thought&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take Plato&amp;rsquo;s Republic, for example. In ten different books, Socrates and some friends debate on the perfect city (the Kallopolis). Ask any politics student about book number 8, and I can guarantee that, if they are decent students, they will know about it. Contemporary political theory without the contributions of greek authors is incomplete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On The Republic, I was particularly impressed by plato&amp;rsquo;s cave and the construction of the Kallopolis within oneself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plato&amp;rsquo;s cave&lt;/strong&gt; is a popular alegory (a quick google search will teach you more than I ever can), but it gets you thinking of our definition of reality. The limitation of what&amp;rsquo;s real to what we can percieve as so is great topic for reflection for anyone with a bit of extra time in their hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plato also mentions that the best location for the perfect city is on someone&amp;rsquo;s soul. Phylosophical crazyness or not, it triggered some crazy shit in my head. Recently I read the Dalai Lama&amp;rsquo;s autobiography, which probably made my &amp;ldquo;meditation&amp;rdquo; switch go on (when I learn something new, I usually link it to anything for a time after), but I certainly recommend reflecting on the building of a perfect entity within oneself following the Plato style: deconstruct anything to first principles and build from there. Better explained, think about what is the next basic step to become who you want to be (&lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; basic). From their, start building the perfect city inside you (now that sounds weired)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;on-science&#34;&gt;On science&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On science, greeks did not lag behind either. If you&amp;rsquo;re lucky enough to get your hands on a copy of &lt;strong&gt;Isaac Asimovs&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Universe&lt;/em&gt; (or any other book that explains the cosmos) you&amp;rsquo;ll notice that the greeks are the clear winners if the historical space race. It was them that first theorized about the shape of the earth of the universe. It was also them who first attempted to measure distances of the cosmos (with relative success). It was also them that discovered the same planets (from &lt;em&gt;planetes&lt;/em&gt;, wanderer).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On measuring distances, the truth is their calculations were quite off (usually underestimated the size of things, but who can blame them). However, some estimations were scaringly close. Hipparchus of Nicaea (first person to draw parallels and meridians, btw) calculated that distance to the moon was 30 times the Earth&amp;rsquo;s diameter, or around 384 000 kilometers. The true average distance? A little bit over 400 km more. Less than a 1% error. No further questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a bit comical that greek geographers defended a spherical shaped earth from as early as the sixth century a.D. It appears that nowadays some people lag more than 2500 years in knowledge and somehow we are not concerned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I could go on and on and on&amp;hellip; Pythagoras and his famous theorem, Aristotles crying &lt;em&gt;eureka&lt;/em&gt; when understanding buoyancy or Euclid laying the foundation for geometry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;on-gymnastics&#34;&gt;On &lt;em&gt;gymnastics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greeks were not stay at home nerds. No, no, not these greeks. Few societies have placed as much importance in the health of the body. Most great thinkers build the &amp;ldquo;perfect man&amp;rdquo; on a combination of both physical and mental excellence. It took a while for Rousseau to restart the trende to combina physical and cognitive training for eduation. Once again, one step ahead of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are talking about the people that came up with the Olympics, which were most certainly not taken lightly. The olympic time was a period in which ongoing wars were consciously stopped to allow athletes to compete. Confronted nations put their differences apart un order to participate in sports. To that level was physical excellence important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is clear now physical activity is essential for ones wellbeing, but for a long time it was not that clear. Greeks, however, never doubted its importance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 2000 years ago, a group of men decided to dedicate their lives to advance humanity in the road of understanding, and most of us live ignorant to their sacrifice. Never has their been such an involvement in the development of knowledge, and what&amp;rsquo;s more, never has a step as big been taken towards understanding than in Ancient Greece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is a call for reflection. I have summarised very few of their achievements, yet I has to cut most of what I had written short, even with leaving art out of the question. Many would recommend you to further research on their achievements, but I would only recommend doing so if you don&amp;rsquo;t mind jumping straight into a rabbit hole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always been told to look at what the intelligent people around me are doing. They were reading, &amp;rsquo;the greeks&amp;rsquo; and I followed (reluctantly at first, I must admit). However, on top of the content, what most impacted me were the greeks themselves. What were they thinking when they decided to take such a complicate quest to understand? What made them believe it was worth it? Why work on leaving something behind? All questions to which I&amp;rsquo;m slowly trying to find answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is not only powerful, but also beautiful. Knowledge tells a story. A very interesting story. And for some reason, it is worth it to have your name written in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If it&amp;rsquo;s nor right, don&amp;rsquo;t do it; if its&amp;rsquo; not true, don&amp;rsquo;t say it&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;~ &lt;em&gt;Marcus Aurelius&lt;/em&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On things #1 - On NFT Incomprehension, Crossing the Chasm</title>
      <link>https://ddesotto.com/posts/on-nft-incomprehension/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 17:02:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ddesotto.com/posts/on-nft-incomprehension/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;callout&#34;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&#34;callout-inner&#34;&gt;
    ⚠️ DISCLAIMER. NFTs are a very risky asset. This is not financial advice
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NFT&amp;rsquo;s are a &amp;ldquo;thing&amp;rdquo; now. At least for a growing group of believers. With daily sales of these assets approaching the $100 million mark and Beeple making headlines with his &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/11/arts/design/nft-auction-christies-beeple.html&#34;&gt;$69 million digital collage sale&lt;/a&gt;, interest for this new type of digital assets is spreading like an epidemic. However, they have not gone down well for all people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;on-nfts&#34;&gt;On NFTs&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-fungible tokens, NFTs for short, are &amp;ldquo;proofs of ownership in the blockchain&amp;rdquo;. Their most popular form right now is in the form of digital art (visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensea.com&#34;&gt;Opensea&lt;/a&gt; to see some of examples) but use cases from real estate to medical records and IP. Remember, blockchains are immutable ledgers. Keeping a record of ownership in them is just a way to secure authenticity. The same way you can verify transactions, smart contracts allow for the verification of ownerhip in networks like Ethereum and Solana. For more on NFT&amp;rsquo;s, you can check out this &lt;a href=&#34;https://ethereum.org/en/nft/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; on the Ethereum blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-rise-to-where&#34;&gt;The rise&amp;hellip; to where?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It comes without question that NFT adoption is growing, specially in developing countries. A Finder report on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.finder.com/ph/nft-statistics&#34;&gt;2021 NFT statistics&lt;/a&gt; showed that current ownerhip of NFTs as a percentage of total population averaged 11.6% in surveyed countries, with a 20.9% projection expected for following years. Although the US lags behind with only 3 in every 10 owning a digital asset, catalysts like Facebook&amp;rsquo;s name change to Meta,  augur a great future in the years to come. NFTs are on the road to mass adoption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having said that, it is not being an easy path. The growing number of adopters has been matched by an also rising number of &amp;ldquo;haters&amp;rdquo; that believe NFTs are a scam built to take money away from the newcomers with hopes on profiting on this new gold rush. And they are right, mostly. Pricing a hyped asset that promises infinite use cases is complicated. When Internet first started becoming useful for the average citizen, anything related to it was thought to be the future. In this battle it was internet bulls that ended up being right, but detractors were not completely wrong. Of the companies that were around, very few survived and those that did, took a bit hit i.e it took Amazon to reach its dotcom ATH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet &lt;em&gt;WAS&lt;/em&gt; the new next thing, but success does not happen overnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;early-adopters-vs-general-public&#34;&gt;Early-adopters vs general public&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SnoopDogg/status/1484586102182727682&#34;&gt;Snoop Dogg&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jimmyfallon/status/1459164143626424321&#34;&gt;Jimmy Fallon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Eminem?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1477005759359733771%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fcryplogger.com%2Feminem-buys-nft-bored-ape-yacht-club-for-450000%2F&#34;&gt;Eminem&lt;/a&gt; (to mention a few) are right about NFTs or not, I fear the current battle between digital asset optimists and pesimists is very similar to the internet craze of the late 90s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These types of battles are not rare in new technologies: early-adopters that are quicker to understand the value proposition (and some opportunists looking to make quick money) face the skepticism of the general public, reluctant to &amp;ldquo;cross the chasm&amp;rdquo;. To represent this confrontation, it is useful to be familiar with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bigbangpartnership.co.uk/045-an-introduction-to-product-development-using-two-classical-concepts-the-product-lifecycle-and-the-innovation-adoption-curve/&#34;&gt;Gartner Hype Cycle&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://thinkinsights.net/strategy/crossing-the-chasm/&#34;&gt;Technology Adoption Curve&lt;/a&gt;. A combination of the two perfectly depicts my view on NFTs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://setandbma.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/technology-adoption.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Plot of the Hype Cycle against the Tech Adoption Curve&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;h4&gt;Hype Cycle vs Tech Adoption&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Gartner Hype Cycle&lt;/strong&gt; is a tool used to map hype for a product against time. Introduction of the product/technology is followed by a growth in expectations, as speculations for its possible use cases reach bizarre extremes (world domination, for the most radical believers). However, humans are impatient beings, and delays in reaching this sometimes &lt;em&gt;a bit&lt;/em&gt; high expectations make people lose interest on the product, leaving only the rational and the crazy routing for technology&amp;rsquo;s success. Eventually, the curve flattens as realistic use cases start to see adoption (or product/technology falls into oblivion).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Technology Adoption Curve&lt;/strong&gt; maps the number of new users from launch. The relation is built in quite a logical manner: marketing for a product is most complicated in the early stages, reaches its most efficient stage when organic growth is at its highest (new users come refered by other users) and some &amp;ldquo;laggards&amp;rdquo; resist when product penetration is at its highest. Basics aside, the most important concept to understand here is what many marketers call the &amp;ldquo;chasm&amp;rdquo;, which is the step you have to take from going from your early-adopter community to the average consumer (&lt;em&gt;Geoffrey Moore&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/-/es/Geoffrey-Moore/dp/0062292986&#34;&gt;Crossing the Chasm&lt;/a&gt; talks about this in depth).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consulting firm Gartner places NFTs on peak hype right now, claiming they could be &lt;a href=&#34;https://decrypt.co/79572/gartner-hype-cycle-ranks-nfts-peak-inflated-expectations-amid-craze&#34;&gt;5 years away from reaching mass adoption&lt;/a&gt;, a much more advanced scenario than the one faced by DeFi, for example, that is still lagginf in the &lt;em&gt;Innovation Trigger&lt;/em&gt; phase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images-cdn.welcomesoftware.com/Zz01ZmY4NGU1ZTAwZjgxMWVjYWI3MjY1MjhkNjNjMWEzNw==?token=eyJ0eXAiOiJKV1QiLCJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJzdWIiOlsiNWZmODRlNWUwMGY4MTFlY2FiNzI2NTI4ZDYzYzFhMzciXSwiZXhwIjoxNjQyMDgzMjUwfQ.oy7Nr0QTGC7CWKxiY0rvMJmc3SCsi3rOdl9kp-VJnIA&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;h4&gt;Hype Cycle for 2021 emergent technologies&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My view on the current adoption of NFTs is that there is a disconnect between innovators and the early majority when it comes to hype, signaling the product has not quite crossed the chasm. On the one hand we have newcomers excited about their new discovery, and on the other, a confused majority that is alien to their excitement and, in most cases correctly, call them a scam and warn about a &amp;ldquo;NFT bubble&amp;rdquo;. Both try to be on the winning side of the argument, and whether you argue that NFTs are worthless or, on the opposite, believe they are the future of ownerhip, the truth is you will probably be right. Unfortunate as it may be, it is not black or white when it comes to the future of these tokens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;ignorance&#34;&gt;Ignorance&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I see it, it is true that 90% of projects will become worthless, leaving thousands if not millions bagholding. And maybe 90% is a conservative guess. Most P2E games introduce NFTsjust for the sake of doing so, with litte to no need for them, metaverse land investors are bidding exorbitant amounts trying to anticipate rising prices in what may be too much anticipation and some average buyers are tricked into buying digital art from artists that only &lt;em&gt;may be&lt;/em&gt; the next Beeple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, a bad use of the technology does not correlate with a bad technology. Use cases for NFTs are not imaginary. I, for example, predict a great future in real estate and digital art. In many cases, detractors cherry pick&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;closing-remarks&#34;&gt;Closing remarks&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My view on the current adoption of NFTs is that there is a disconnect between innovators and the early majority when it comes to hype, signaling the product has not quite crossed the chasm. On the one hand we have newcomers excited Both try to be on the winning side of the argument, and whether you argue that NFTs are worthless or, on the opposite, believe they are the future of ownerhip, the truth is you will probably be right. Unfortunate as it may be, it is not black or white when it comes to the future of these tokens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has happened with the internet, e-commerce, machine learning and AI, wearable tech, blockhain (2017 + blockhain in your startup name = million dollar funding series), delivery, real estate i-buyers etc. and is happening with EVs. It could also be happening with NFTs. Only time will tell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My recommendation for enthusiasts is to try and be pessimistic for a day to try and find any flaws in the current state of the market. If you can&amp;rsquo;t find any, then maybe you&amp;rsquo;re too naive. The same goes for those who criticize them with little to no understanding about how &lt;em&gt;the WHOLE&lt;/em&gt; ecosystem works. Try read a book, a news article or even a Twitter thread. Worst thing that can happen is you learn something. If you keep crying wolf, nobody will believe you when the wolf really comes, and an I told you, on either side, is of little to no help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to confront me on anything mentioned in this article, I will be glad to answer in &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:info.desotto@gmail.com&#34;&gt;info.desotto@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;. No spam please! 😃&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;strong&gt;JPG File Sells for $69 Million, as ‘NFT Mania’ Gathers Pace&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;New York Times.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/11/arts/design/nft-auction-christies-beeple.html&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;strong&gt;Non-fungible tokens (NFT)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Ethereum Foundation.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://ethereum.org/en/nft/&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] &lt;strong&gt;NFT statistics 2021&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Finder&lt;/em&gt; . &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.finder.com/nft-statistics&#34;&gt;&amp;#x1f517;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[4] &lt;strong&gt;Gartner Hype Cycle&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Gartner&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gartner.com/en/research/methodologies/gartner-hype-cycle#:~:text=goals-,How%20do%20you%20use,Clients,-use&#34;&gt;&amp;#x1f517;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[5] &lt;strong&gt;Crossing the Chasm&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Geoffrey Moore&lt;/em&gt;.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/-/es/Geoffrey-Moore/dp/0062292986/?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;pd_rd_w=AknGt&amp;amp;pf_rd_p=6f8f01b9-e98c-4b0d-91cf-a93790267134&amp;amp;pf_rd_r=728CG9QVDQQ0ERDJ7J0B&amp;amp;pd_rd_r=8fcdebb8-a82e-4549-b108-ba699d325588&amp;amp;pd_rd_wg=2weOU&amp;amp;ref_=pd_gw_ci_mcx_mr_hp_atf_m&#34;&gt;&amp;#x1f4d6;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hightechstrategies.com/crossing-the-chasm-summary/&#34;&gt;&amp;#x1f517;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[6] &lt;strong&gt;3 Themes Surface in the 2021 Hype Cycle for Emerging Technologies&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Gartner&lt;/em&gt;.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gartner.com/smarterwithgartner/3-themes-surface-in-the-2021-hype-cycle-for-emerging-technologies&#34;&gt;&amp;#x1f517;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>diegodesotto\raw - the Why</title>
      <link>https://ddesotto.com/posts/diegodesottoraw-thewhy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 13:21:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ddesotto.com/posts/diegodesottoraw-thewhy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-ddesottoraw&#34;&gt;Why ddesotto\raw&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried &lt;strong&gt;WordPress&lt;/strong&gt;. Now I&amp;rsquo;m here, which should be enough of a summary on how my &lt;strong&gt;WordPress&lt;/strong&gt; experience went (spoiler alert, do not recommend).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My blog, &lt;strong&gt;bigdtalks.com&lt;/strong&gt;, lasted one eternal year. While live, it hosted 15 posts with an average of 100 views/post, which is not bad, considering I had no prior experience. I built the site on Elementor (who calls that customizable?) and used BlueHost for buying the domain and hosting. Overall, the site came to a cost of around &lt;strong&gt;$160&lt;/strong&gt;. You might be wondering how much the ROI was. Well, the answer is not that good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first I set up the site with the vision of having a possible source for passive income at the same time I shared my passion for acquiring knowledge. My idea was to use my already regular research sprees to then write articles on those topics. The perfect synergy. The problem is I became to focused on the former while forgetting the latter. A sidenote on building side-projects: &lt;strong&gt;focus on quality, and money will follow&lt;/strong&gt;. Lesson learned 👍.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having said that, those &lt;strong&gt;$160&lt;/strong&gt; were probably the best investment I made in 2021 (and yes, I also bought &lt;strong&gt;ETH&lt;/strong&gt; 😃). I have learned a lot from &lt;strong&gt;bigdtalks.com&lt;/strong&gt;. I tried to reach perfection when, first, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really know what perfection was, and second, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t even tested if my idea was good enough. So for this blog, first publish, then ask. Good thing I can extrapolate it to practically any aspect of life. Thanks to my &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;failed&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; blog, I have now become more confident on making mistakes. I hope I learned the right lesson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-github-pages--hugo&#34;&gt;Why Github Pages + Hugo&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have never been a Github groupie. Most of my projects went unnoticed to the general public, small scripts to automate basic tasks or to make use of a fancy algorithm I had learned about not so long ago. However, after I replaced &lt;strong&gt;IG&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;TikTok&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;strong&gt;Twitter&lt;/strong&gt;, and having a small affection for HackerNews, where Github-related postings are a regular, hosting this website with GithubPages looked like an excellent way to make it both customizable &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; simple. Oh yes, and also very cheap 💸.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided on Hugo over Jekyll inspired by a fellow blogger (if I can call myself that) I found on HackerNews, &lt;strong&gt;Kris Machowski&lt;/strong&gt;. I really liked the simplicity and layout of his site and decided to use it as &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;inspiration&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. By the way, his content is incredible, so please check it out &lt;a href=&#34;https://machow.ski&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. You won&amp;rsquo;t regret it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;objectives&#34;&gt;Objectives&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have decided to set a list of objectives before a start as a way of setting waypoints to measure the success of this blog. Nothing complicated, but more of a test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20 blog posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;100 newsletter subscribers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;100 visitors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building a useful relationship through the blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Featured on HackerNews Top5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having revenue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep it running at least 5 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>