<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on ddesotto\raw</title><link>https://ddesotto.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on ddesotto\raw</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© ddesotto</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 13:32:34 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ddesotto.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>But actually, what is dust?</title><link>https://ddesotto.com/posts/what-is-dust/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 13:32:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ddesotto.com/posts/what-is-dust/</guid><description>A table is table, a chair is a chair, and a lamp is, indeed, a lamp. At least from a broad perspective. You are also describing a lamp when saying &amp;ldquo;an illuminating device, generally composed of a stand and a bulb&amp;rdquo; The stand and the bulb are as much lamp as the object itself, but at the same time, completely different entities.
The whole world is built by these types of constructions.</description></item><item><title>On things #2 - On Greeks and Knowledge</title><link>https://ddesotto.com/posts/on-greeks-and-knowledge/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 12:09:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ddesotto.com/posts/on-greeks-and-knowledge/</guid><description>Last week I finished reading Plato&amp;rsquo;s Republic. The week before, Rhetorics by Aristotle. Not so long ago, Meditations by Marcus Aurelius. A complete ancient greek reading spree, which I most certainly most regret (they have me backordered on Seneca&amp;rsquo;s Letters from a Stoic 😢).
Honestly, what were these guys on when they wrote all this.
If I had to choose a phrase to represent my average impression, without doubt I would choose &amp;ldquo;wow&amp;hellip; what?</description></item><item><title>On things #1 - On NFT Incomprehension, Crossing the Chasm</title><link>https://ddesotto.com/posts/on-nft-incomprehension/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 17:02:51 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ddesotto.com/posts/on-nft-incomprehension/</guid><description>⚠️ DISCLAIMER. NFTs are a very risky asset. This is not financial advice NFT&amp;rsquo;s are a &amp;ldquo;thing&amp;rdquo; now. At least for a growing group of believers. With daily sales of these assets approaching the $100 million mark and Beeple making headlines with his $69 million digital collage sale, interest for this new type of digital assets is spreading like an epidemic. However, they have not gone down well for all people.</description></item><item><title>diegodesotto\raw - the Why</title><link>https://ddesotto.com/posts/diegodesottoraw-thewhy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 13:21:14 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ddesotto.com/posts/diegodesottoraw-thewhy/</guid><description>Why ddesotto\raw I tried WordPress. Now I&amp;rsquo;m here, which should be enough of a summary on how my WordPress experience went (spoiler alert, do not recommend).
My blog, bigdtalks.com, lasted one eternal year. While live, it hosted 15 posts with an average of 100 views/post, which is not bad, considering I had no prior experience. I built the site on Elementor (who calls that customizable?) and used BlueHost for buying the domain and hosting.</description></item></channel></rss>